



Sulkhanov Ilya

Male, 33 years, born on 9 March 1989

+90 (534) 6065562

ilya.sulkhanov@gmail.com — preferred means of communication

Another site: https://github.com/Iluxmas

Reside in: Turkey

Citizenship: Russia, work permit at: Russia Ready to relocate, ready for rare business trips

Desired position and salary

Front-end Developer

Specializations:

- Other
- Programmer, developer
 Employment: part time, full time

Work schedule: remote working Desired travel time to work: any

Work experience — 11 years 5 months

December 2022
— till now
3 months

Flying Academy, Prague

Web developer

- Developed 10+ mobile-friendly pages for students assessment portal.
- Redesigned existing pages using UI/UX good practices to enhance user experience.
- Created new functionality using Javascript.
- Collaborated with backend developer to improve web page usability.
- Created designs that satisfied business objectives and user needs.

October 2022 — January 2023 4 months

Freelance

Frontend Developer

- Created React components for CRM app
- Wrote functionality with Javascript, including async for interaction with cloud DB Firebase Stack: React, Styled-components, Firebase.

April 2022 — January 2023 10 months

Yandex Practicum

Front-end developer (education)

► Diploma project - Filmopoisk

Deployed: https://kino.nomoredomains.club/

Stack: React, JavaScript, NodeJs, MongoDB, REST Api

Description: App with registration and authorization, there is feature of movie search in the DB,

saving the movie to favourites. App has responsive layout down to 320 px width.

Repo front: https://github.com/Iluxmas/movies-explorer-frontend

Repo back: https://github.com/Iluxmas/movies-explorer-api

► Project #1 - Resume page

Link: https://iluxmas.github.io/resume/

Stack: React, JavaScript, Webpack

Description: My pet-project where I gathered all information about me in one page, for easier sharing

with recruiters. It has RU and EN version, EN loading when you device language is not RU. Page is adaptive and I also tried to keep design light. Follow the next link to find more info. Repo: https://github.com/Iluxmas/resume

► Project #2: Mesto App

Stack: JavaScript, API, Webpack, Express, MongoDB, Git

Description: Project theme was photo social network. Template was taken from Figma. Page is adaptive, size and position of elements depends on screen size. ApiService class component responsible for server-client interaction. Bundling made with Webpack. Later project was ported to React, backend was configurated on Express, MongoDB was used as database.

Repo: https://github.com/Iluxmas/mesto

► Project #3 : Todo list app

Stack: React.js, JavaScript, Jest

Description: Application todo list. Project was done using React, including Hooks and Class components. At the moment some components are covered with various tests. Features: adding\deleting todos, marking as important\done, filter by name or state.

Repo: https://github.com/Iluxmas/To-do-app

► Project #4 : How-to-learn

Stack: HTML, CSS, BEM, Git, Figma, JS

Description: Project theme was Education Techniques. To create this page I implemented some new knowledges about markup language and css flex. Files organization was made according to BEM nested methodology. Language switch was made with JS.

Repo: https://github.com/Iluxmas/how-to-learn

► Project #5 : Russian travel

Stack: HTML, CSS, SCSS, BEM, Git, Figma

Description: Project theme was russian travel, template was taken from Figma. Page is adaptive, size and position of elements depends on screen size through media queries. Grid and flex both were used. For styles SCSS was used with further conversion to css.

Repo: https://github.com/Iluxmas/russian-travel

All projects were code-reviewed.

May 2017 — July 2022 5 years 3 months

Siegwerk

Moscow, www.siegwerk.com/en/home.html

Chemical Production, Fertilizers

• Paint and Varnish Products, Raw Materials (Manufacturing)

Chemist / Senior Chemist / Application technology manager

- Was responsible for regional clients support,
- Managed customer's projects from processing of request to implementing in production,
- Searched causes and solved problems appeared on client production site,
- Have created and adjusted recipes of ink and lacquers under customer needs,
- Planned and performed complex tests using standard company methodics, with result evaluation and reporting,
- Mentored newbie laboratory staff,
- Controlled laboratory functioning in terms of available consumables, cleanliness and order,
- $\boldsymbol{-}$ Worked with recipies, searched for alternative raw materials, performed complex tests of inks,
- Cooperated with technology team and laboratory in Germany,
- Implemented new products on local market,

Wrote a VisualBasic script for data exchange of MS Office applications, which automated previously manual work and saved more than 100 man-hours in 3 years.

The best employee of 2018 in the category "Responsibility".

October 2011 — May 2017 5 years 8 months

FGUP Vims

Moscow, vims-geo.ru/

Junior science researcher

- Worked in team responsible for methodics development and samples analisys,
- Participated in writing of science articles,

Education

Higher

2011

Mendeleev University of Chemical Technology

High Temperature Materials and Technologies Department, Glass technology

Professional development, courses

2022 Yandex Practicum

Yandex, Front-end developer

²⁰²² Udemy

Juriy Bura, React + Redux - Professional Development

2022 Udemy

Ivan Petrychenko, JavaScript + React Complete Course

Key skills

Languages

Russian — Native

English — C1 — Advanced

Skills

HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript Git React.js SCSS БЭМ Webpack Figma Photoshop Адаптивная верстка Express MongoDB

Driving experience

Driver's license category B

Further information

About me

I am Frontend Developer and since 2022 based in Marmaris, Turkey. My background is a chemical technology, job at Siegwerk, world's leading ink supplier, gave me great experience in project managing, product development and business oriented thinking. But, since my big interest in maths and phisics, I was always dreaming about coding, programming always was a part of me. I choose Frontend cause I have great sense of beauty. Day-to-day websurfing just show that good FE developers is still in need. Also I love challenges and to solve puzzles, because don't like questions without an answer. I am really happy that I can bring my vision, skills and experience to the WEB",

Love snowboarding at winter, bicycle trips in summer, rock climbing and traveling, 32 countries at the moment.